all right what's up guys welcome back to
another video so in this video we're
gonna be talking about how i use my ema
part two so if you guys haven't seen
part one make sure to go click the link
in the description below and i assure
you guys kind of like an introduction to
it this is like a little more advanced
um it's very simple everybody
complicates it they think it has like a
secret you know secret sauce to it like
it's a secret way to use it it's really
not just an added confidence and when
you guys see the video uh later on in
just a little bit it's gonna make a lot
more sense so um with that being said
make sure to watch the video all the way
to the end hella gems dropped in the
video because it's just
not over complicated it's straight to
the point if you haven't seen part one
make sure to go watch part one because
uh i say a little bit of things in part
one that create the foundation obviously
for part two right these are very simple
videos so make sure you go watch the
video and i'll see you guys now in the
charts
oh quick update so i still have the the
rose rice the mclaren is almost out of
the shop um it's been in the shop like
six months uh it's literally about to
get out but i'm thinking of trading the
rose for something else so i don't know
what do you guys think i should maybe
trade it for i'm uh i'm looking to do
something with it not sure yet damn
damn
all right what's up guys now that we're
here in the charts we're gonna talk
about how i use my ema part two like i
said if you guys haven't seen the part
one make sure to go to my channel go
make sure to go watch part one part one
it's a very simple basic introduction
i'm just gonna put this up here just in
case if you guys haven't seen part one
because i don't you know just to avoid
the question what ema do i use i use the
the 50 ema
the source is closed
the offset is zero the style that i use
is basically kind of the color the stuff
that i use and i have it visible on
every single time frame because i use it
differently on every single type right
so
this video we're gonna do a part two on
how i use my ema like i said i have a
part one which is very simple and you
know understanding of the ema this is
gonna be a part two and the final part
because realistically i could i swear to
god i could trade without the ema like i
don't need this on the screen
i'm not gonna lie i'm transitioning to
not even using it because it is
affecting my trading just a little bit
because i do rely on it a little bit
sometimes just simply because i um i
over like i overlook that what that
market is actually doing and then i base
it off of the ema and it's wrong like
having the e like having an ema is just
an added confluence you guys need to
understand that like this is not gonna
make me profitable this is not gonna not
make me profitable this is not gonna
make me win or lose more
this is a very simple concept whenever i
trade i trade based off of a confluence
trading so i need a certain amount of
trades i mean i need a certain amount of
confluences
to take a trade let's say right now you
have certain requirements for you to
let's say
buy a car i need it to be a specific
color i need it to have specific miles i
need for it to have a specific um
interior specific spec whatever the case
is it's the same thing with this all
this is doing is just adding or removing
a spec to the car that you're looking to
buy so like i said this is going to be a
very simple explanation it's just an
add-on to basically what i have already
explained and it's very very simple i'm
going to go on multiple different
examples of exactly on which time frame
i take it but to be honest it really
doesn't get any more complex than this
so basically kind of how i explained in
the past obviously this is gj this ema
works on any pair and i will be honest
for me it probably works best on other
pairs that are not gj for me gj is
probably um the best
pair to trade when it comes to market
structure not the ema i feel like every
pair should be market structure first
versus ema but for this example i'm
going to show you guys how beautiful
this is so to touch up again the ema is
used as a dynamic support and resistance
same way how you can mark up a level of
support and resistance like this
level of resistance use that support
same thing vice versa you come here
level of support used as resistance
level of
support through here and i could just go
on hundreds of examples of support and
resistance right this is the same exact
thing as you can tell here this ema when
you are under it it uses it as
resistance when you are under it uses it
as resistance when you are above it it
uses it as support right very simple but
this obviously changes throughout all of
the time frames but the concept is
exactly the same the concept is the same
meaning if we're above it on the daily
we could use it as support we're under
around daily it uses it as resistance
but
when it comes to actually taking a trade
with the ema what time frame am i
looking to take a trade with the ema so
i don't really care for the daily for me
like if we could be above it on the
daily and we're looking to buy cool if
we're on it when we're selling cool i
don't really care for it to be
completely honest because the higher
time frames i care more about market
structure and the actual trend with what
we're doing so we're above it on the
weekly or daily to me it's completely
relevant i can just simply do this so i
really don't care this right here is
probably like one of my juiciest trades
that i've ever taken in my life
in my life and noticed how it was i was
selling and notice how the ema was way
down here like i did not care that the
ema was under so i actually took this
trade from what i remember
on the four hour and this trade is just
so beautiful like i can probably break
this trade down on another um another
time but this is the trade that i made
like almost 70k on but this shows you
the example how i was using the ema as a
dynamic level of support and then
resistance notice how this is an added
confluence if i simply take off the ema
i'm selling at a level of support as
resistance you zoom in i have my bearish
engulfing candlestick entry signal and
so on done having the ema there's like
oh and
the car has low miles or the car has uh
an exhaust or it has better sound
whatever it's just an add-on it's just a
plus it doesn't
make or break the deal i need you guys
to really understand that so let's just
go on in this example right here this
trade right here well let me take it
back a step right so whenever i go take
a trade i don't really care if whether
we're above it or under on the weekly
time frame for me it's irrelevant on the
higher time frames when you go down to
the lower time frame such as the four
hour two hour one hour this is where it
starts getting a little bit more
detailed because as you can tell it
shifts from being used as
resistance to them you used as support
to their resistance and then support to
then support all through here to then
resistance very very frequently because
obviously the lower timeframes are
moving a lot faster than the higher time
frames so when it comes to doing this i
personally myself if i'm looking to buy
i much
like would much rather have it be above
if i'm looking to sell i would much
rather have it be under but for this
example right here as you can tell
it wasn't relevant because i'm selling
at a level of support at that is used as
resistance that is stronger to me
that we are above the one hour ema who
cares like i'm telling you just take
this off
boom tell me how clean that doesn't look
level of support resistance bearish
engulfing so this is what you guys need
to understand and don't overthink it
don't overlook it don't just complicate
it like trade what you see not what you
think or what you're creating to see
like no yes
you're seeing it that it's above the ema
but you're just
completely dismissing everything else
that the markets are literally showing
you right you go down to the two hour
where did it go you see here on the two
hour and the two hour we were above it
as well the four hour we were under it
so this is what i explained to you guys
that it's just it could get very
confusing and you could get you could
just go all over the place that's why i
just simply say if you can add it on
cool that added on but don't determine
your trade to it so when i go take a
trade like i said the higher time frames
for me would be a big doesn't really
matter like if it's there even better
and then when it comes to the lower time
frames i would ideally want to be under
or above if i'm selling i would want to
be under if i'm buying i would obviously
want to be above it and it just creates
an added confluence and it could you
know just give you more peace of mind
and more confidence that you're going
with the trend it's almost like drawing
a trend line something like this and you
can see like basically we're above it i
don't use trendline strengths to me are
super submissive like you could just
literally put it however you want i mean
super subjective um you can literally
put it however you want so that's just
to me
but there's really nothing else to it i
mean i don't really care for it i i
honestly have it on there because it
looks cool and like i use it sometimes
here and there it's an added confidence
but realistically now i'm you know i'm
getting a lot more mature with my
trading a lot more experienced i am
honestly at a time even trading like
this and then maybe with
one line like this
this is all i need on my charts and i
will make
12 15 20 a month i really don't need
anything else it's simply market
structure let's just put that back
because i don't know why that was there
i gotta i gotta know why i take it off
um so like for example this zone right
here is because of obviously level of
resistance you just support whatever so
on and so forth so for example let's say
for this example right here where we are
as you can tell the daily we are
technically bullish this market
structure is bullish as you can tell we
remain bullish in here we are
approaching a very strong level of
support and then we happen to be above
the daily ema cool that's an added
confluence you go down to the four hour
let's say the four hour you're looking
to buy technically this four hour time
frame is bullish so as you can see here
we are creating high higher low high
higher low technically we're bearish
actually and then we can actually come
into this area and use this as a left
head right shoulder and then sell from
the four hour ema or if we break above
we then wait for the re-test and now
we're re-testing at a level of support
resistance resistance but now we're
re-testing the ema same exact thing
right here let's say we would have been
buying at this embroidery head and
shoulders right here so here left head
and then the right shoulder
let's say it would have played out you
would have bought here but let's say it
doesn't play out cool you react and
adapt you then wait for the pullback and
then the same area you were looking to
buy now you sell out along with the ema
that's it just go with the trend set and
forget very simple i mean to me the ema
like it's just something that i feel
like people got to get out of the system
just really understand it so i just kind
of want to make this simple very simple
very you know like
um any beginner can understand it and
just get through your head that you
don't need it you don't need it we need
to understand is what is going on here
if you can properly identify it to me in
this zone right here where we went
bullish and where we went bearish with
the market structure trust me you by
yourself are gonna do this it's like
them that's annoying my chart tell me
you just don't see so much more by just
simply taking off that little line
there's a lot of people that they also
have this on their charts and i don't
know why to me it's very annoying and to
me it's very cringe but what do you need
to have this on your chart for
why do you need to have a watermark
there like do you see how it is
literally blocking
this you can't see that
tell me the difference of there
versus here now you can actually see
what is going on why do you need to see
that watermark if you're a trader just
by looking at the chart you would know
what pair you're on like you don't need
to be constantly reminded of it simply
take off that watermark so you can see
what is going on if you have that
blocking you you literally cannot see
and trading is a business that you have
to see what you're taking this isn't
music you're listening to it or feeling
what no this is what you see so make
sure that you have your charts clean and
you are trading what you see not what
you think so i know i want a little bit
of a tangent there kind of went a little
bit all over the place but it's just my
um
approach to the markets nowadays and
then to me it's just the truth i'm
giving you guys my truth to my reality
of my trading i'm not going to tell you
guys a dream that i have a super secret
ema and it's a hundred percent worry no
bro like i swear to god i could just
take this off and it will not affect me
at all
so um i appreciate you guys watching the
video all the way to the end you guys
want to see any other videos make sure
to drop a comment it helps me it really
does help me get all these videos out
there because it's um
now i don't want to say hard but it is
very uh time consuming to just think of
a video create it upload it so if you
guys give me an idea i just basically
run with it flow with it and then it'll
um
it'll help out a lot more so uh stay
tuned to this friday's podcast that you
guys already know setting up center
figure podcast number one forex trading
podcast
and yeah i hope to see you guys in the
next video make sure to join the free
telegram i got a lot of crazy things
coming in the free telegram um there's
just going to be so much going on there
stay tuned for the updates and i'll see
you guys in the next video